<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Hugo Atlantic</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Hugo Atlantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</managingEditor><webMaster>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://subhashydv.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring the Distinctions Between Kotlin and Java</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2024/05/exploring-the-distinctions-between-kotlin-and-java/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 17:33:51 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2024/05/exploring-the-distinctions-between-kotlin-and-java/</guid><description>About Kotlin : Kotlin is a programming language, that runs on Java Virtual Machines (JVMs) and that can also be compiled to JavaScript. This programming language is statically typed, which means that variables, functions, and expressions use predefined sets of types that can be checked on compile time.
How kotlin is different from java Java and Kotlin both are widely used programming languages, but there are some differences. Lets see these difference :</description></item><item><title>Intro to Kafka</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2023/09/intro-to-kafka/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 20:26:12 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2023/09/intro-to-kafka/</guid><description>In this blog I will try to answer few question that we might have as a beginner. So let&amp;rsquo;s start with our first question :
What is kafka? So let&amp;rsquo;s think kafka as a central hub that allows someone to host and consume the live data (stream). In kafka&amp;rsquo;s term the host and consumer will be called producer and consumer respectively. There can be multiple producer and consumer to it.</description></item><item><title>Terraform</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2023/01/terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 10:38:29 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2023/01/terraform/</guid><description>Why we need Terraform Before we deep dive understanding about terraform lets understand the problem first. Why do we need this tool or what is the problem we are solving using terraform.
We are going to understand the problem using a simple example. Lets say we are setting some infrastructure for our project. On the first day we don&amp;rsquo;t no what all thing we need in future. Things in the sense we might need some tool or service (like SaaS, PaaS or IaaS).</description></item><item><title>Rappelling</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/09/rappelling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 17:44:05 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/09/rappelling/</guid><description>Rappelling Rappelling is also known as abseiling. It&amp;rsquo;s a technique to climbing down the mountain. This technique is used by mountaineer, climbers, rescuer and defense training.
Many climbers use this technique to protect established anchors from damage. Rope access technicians also use this as a method to access difficult-to-reach areas from above for various industrial applications like maintenance, construction, inspection and welding.
For doing rappelling people should take expert advise and safety measure.</description></item><item><title>Cluedo</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/09/cluedo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 19:25:46 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/09/cluedo/</guid><description>Cluedo Play Game
About Game Cluedo is known as Clue in North America, is a murder mystery game for three to six players that was devised in 1943.
The object of the game is to find out who murdered the game&amp;rsquo;s victim, where the crime took place, and which weapon was used. Each player assumes the role of one of the six suspects and attempts to find the correct answer by strategically moving around a game board representing the rooms of a mansion and collecting clues about the circumstances of the murder from the other players.</description></item><item><title>Scotland Yard</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/08/scotland-yard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 20:58:09 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/08/scotland-yard/</guid><description>Scotland Yard Play Game About Game Scotland yard is board game in which detectives tries to catch robber based on robber log. Players can move around streets of London representing board map. It was published in 1983 and received the Spiel des Jahres award in same year.
Game contains 1 game board (a map of Central London) 6 colored playing pieces 138 transportation tickets 5 ferry or move hidable tickets 2 &amp;lsquo;double-move&amp;rsquo; tickets 1 robber travel log Rules One player gets role of &amp;lsquo;Mr.</description></item><item><title>Hugo</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/08/hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 09:32:07 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/08/hugo/</guid><description>About Hugo Hugo is a static site generator.
Want to know more. visit here</description></item><item><title>About Us</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/about/</guid><description>Creating Modern Websites Web design encompasses many different skills and disciplines in the production and maintenance of websites.
Often many individuals will work in teams covering different aspects of the design process, although some designers will cover them all. Web design partially overlaps web engineering in the broader scope of web development.
What is Web Design? User experience is about how a user interacts with, and experiences, a particular product, system or service.</description></item></channel></rss>