<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Hugo Atlantic</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/tags/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Hugo Atlantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</managingEditor><webMaster>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 11:31:06 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://subhashydv.github.io/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Agentic AI – Personal RAG System</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2025/09/agentic-ai-personal-rag-system/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 11:31:06 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2025/09/agentic-ai-personal-rag-system/</guid><description>With all the noise around on AI these days, it’s easy for developers especially beginners to feel overwhelmed. Questions like “How do I start learning AI?” or “Where should I begin?” are common. If you’re asking yourself the same, you’re in the right place. This blog is designed specifically for beginners and will walk you through the basics to help you take your first steps into the world of Agentic AI.</description></item><item><title>n8n</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2025/06/n8n/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 11:59:29 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2025/06/n8n/</guid><description>About n8n : n8n is an open-source workflow automation tool that lets you connect apps, APIs, and services using a visual interface, but more powerful and developer-friendly.
TIP : Its Just an advanced version of jenkins or any automation pipeline. where these automation tool allows us to write scripts and integrate the workflow where n8n directly allows us to integrate applications and tools.
What I can achieve with n8n : Automate repetitive tasks between services (e.</description></item><item><title>Kotlin</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2024/05/kotlin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 17:33:51 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2024/05/kotlin/</guid><description>About Kotlin : Kotlin is a programming language, that runs on Java Virtual Machines (JVMs) and that can also be compiled to JavaScript. This programming language is statically typed, which means that variables, functions, and expressions use predefined sets of types that can be checked on compile time.
How kotlin is different from java Java and Kotlin both are widely used programming languages, but there are some differences. Lets see these difference :</description></item><item><title>Intro to Kafka</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2023/09/intro-to-kafka/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 20:26:12 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2023/09/intro-to-kafka/</guid><description>In this blog I will try to answer few question that we might have as a beginner. So let&amp;rsquo;s start with our first question :
What is kafka? So let&amp;rsquo;s think kafka as a central hub that allows someone to host and consume the live data (stream). In kafka&amp;rsquo;s term the host and consumer will be called producer and consumer respectively. There can be multiple producer and consumer to it.</description></item><item><title>Terraform</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2023/01/terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 10:38:29 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2023/01/terraform/</guid><description>Why we need Terraform Before we deep dive understanding about terraform lets understand the problem first. Why do we need this tool or what is the problem we are solving using terraform.
We are going to understand the problem using a simple example. Lets say we are setting some infrastructure for our project. On the first day we don&amp;rsquo;t no what all thing we need in future. Things in the sense we might need some tool or service (like SaaS, PaaS or IaaS).</description></item><item><title>Hugo</title><link>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/08/hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 09:32:07 +0530</pubDate><author>subhashyadavtw@gmail.com (Subhash Yadav)</author><guid>https://subhashydv.github.io/blog/2022/08/hugo/</guid><description>About Hugo Hugo is a static site generator.
Want to know more. visit here</description></item></channel></rss>